Guide to the Canby Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Canby family papers
1779-1831
MS 126
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
The papers consist of diaries (1779-1831) of Samuel Canby and 24 letters to James Canby from James Asheton Bayard, Outerbridge Horsey, Louis McLane and Samuel White. Also included is a copy of the agricultural almanac for 1819 annotated by Samuel Canby.
Canby family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Henry Seidel Canby, 1955.
Conditions Governing Access
Diaries of Samuel Canby are available on microfilm. Patrons must use FILM HM 240 instead of the originals.
Associated Materials
Diaries of Samuel Canby are available on microfilm (345 frames on 1 reel, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM240.
Biographical / Historical
Samuel Canby, 1751-1832: miller of Brandywine, Delaware, and a practicing Quaker. James Canby, 1781-1858: miller, entrepreneur, and banker in Wilmington and Brandywine, Delaware; president of the Wilmington and Susquehanna Railroad.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of diaries (1779-1831) of Samuel Canby and 24 letters to James Canby from James Asheton Bayard, Outerbridge Horsey, Louis McLane and Samuel White. Also included is a copy of the agricultural almanac for 1819 annotated by Samuel Canby.
Business; Clergy; Families; Brandywine (Del.); Middle Atlantic States; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; United States -- Politics and government; Diaries; Millers; Canby, James, 1781-1858; Canby, Samuel, 1751-1832; American Friends Service Committee
- Inventory
  - Canby, Samuel (1751-1832)
    - Diary
      Conditions Governing Access
      Diaries of Samuel Canby are available on microfilm. Patrons must use FILM HM 240 instead of the originals.
      - 1779-1796 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1819-1825 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - 1826-1831 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Agricultural Almanack for the Year of Our Lord 1819 (annotated) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Canby, James (1781-1858)
    - ALS from Samuel White (1770-1809), 1801 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 8 ALS from Outerbridge Horsey, 1811 December-1812 June (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 14 ALS from James A. Bayard (1767-1815), 1812 March-1813 February (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - ALS from Louis McLane, 1830 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 8)